Finding Aid for the John Egerton Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part II, Chapter 6-Articles (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part II, Chapter 7-Handwritten Notes (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part II, Chapter 7-Articles (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part II, Chapter 7-Articles (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part II, Chapter 7-Articles (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part II, Chapter 8-Handwritten Notes (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part II, Chapter 8-Articles (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interlogue-Handwritten Notes (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 1- Handwritten Notes (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 1-Articles (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 2-Handwritten Notes (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 2-Articles (Box 76, Folder 14)
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 3-Handwritten Notes (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 3-Articles (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 3-Articles (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 4-Handwritten Notes (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 4-Articles (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 5-Handwritten Notes (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 5-Articles (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 5-Articles (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 6-Handwritten Notes (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 6-Articles (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 6-Articles (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 7-Handwritten Notes (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 7-Articles (Box 77, Folder 13)
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 8-Handwritten Notes (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 8-Articles (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 9-Handwritten Notes (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 9-Articles (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 9-Articles (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 10-Handwritten Notes (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 10-Articles (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 10-Articles (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 11-Handwritten Notes (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 11-Articles (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 11-Articles (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part III, Chapter 11-Articles (Box 78, Folder 12)
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 1-Handwritten Notes (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 1-Articles (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 1-Articles (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 2-Handwritten Notes (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 2-Articles (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 2-Articles (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 2-Articles (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 3-Handwritten Notes (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 3-Articles (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 3-Articles (Box 79, Folder 10)
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 4-Handwritten Notes (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 4-Articles (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 4-Articles (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 4-Articles (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Part IV, Chapter 4-Articles (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Epilogue-Handwritten Notes (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Epilogue-Articles (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Epilogue-Articles (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Bibliography-Notes and Articles (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (A-I) (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (J-W) (Box 80, Folder 12)
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Photographs-Photo Log (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Photographs-Black and White Photostats for Printing (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Photographs-Part I (1932-1938 and Before) Black and White Photos (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Photographs-Part II (1939-August, 1945, World War II) Black and White Photos (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Photographs-Part III (September, 1945-1950) Black and White Photos (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Photographs-Part III (1951-May, 1954 and Beyond) Black and White Photos (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Photographs-Part I-Photocopies (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Photographs-Part II-Photocopies (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Photographs-Part III-Photocopies (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Photographs-Part IV-Photocopies (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Photographs-Zora Neale Thurston from the Library of Congress Photo Archive (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - Photographs-March of Time Newsreels (April, 1944) (Box 81, Folder 12)
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Photographs-Photocopies (Mary McCloud Bethune, Paul Robeson and Others) (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Photographs-Culls (Photos from Part I through Part IV) (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Photographs-Culls (Photocopies, Senate Collection) (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Photographs-Culls (Photocopies, Miscellaneous) (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Photographs-Culls (Photocopies and a few Photographs, Miscellaneous) (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Photographs-Photo Captions (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Photographs-Letters for Permission to Use Photographs (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Photographs-1940s Photo Permission Letters (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Photographs-1940s Photo Permission Letters (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Photographs-1940s Photo Permission Letters (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Photographs-Photo Miscellany (Epilogue) (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Photographs-Photo Miscellany (Epilogue) (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Photographs-Negatives, Extra Prints and Other Materials from Photocopying Work Done by Steve Oden (Box 82, Folder 13)
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Reviews-Journals (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Reviews-Journals (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Reviews-Newspapers (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Reviews-Newspapers (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Reviews-Newspapers (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Promotional Materials (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Prizes/Awards (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Related Materials (Box 83, Folder 8)
- Speak Now Against the Day (1994)
  - Tapes
    - Two Tapes-Gene Graham, Civil Rights Leader, Woodmont Christian Church, Nashville, TN, 1950s; Taped interviews-11/30/81, 2/1/82, 2/4/82 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Four Tapes-John Egerton Interview with Robert Penn Warren, March 1-4, 1979 (2 Tapes) and April 2, 1979 (2 tapes) (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Three Tapes-John Egerton with John Popham, 3/22/86 and 10/20/86 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - One Tape-Studs Terkel with John Egerton, 11/3/94 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - The Potomac Chronicle (Harold and Virginia Fleming, with Introduction by John Egerton-1996)-Manuscript of Egerton’s Introduction (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - The Potomac Chronicle-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - The Potomac Chronicle-Publicity (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Berea College Commencement Address and Honorary Degree (1996)-Manuscript (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Berea College Commencement Address-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Berea College Commencement Address-Degree and Citation (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Berea College Commencement Address-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Berea College Commencement Address-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Berea College Commencement Address-Publicity (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Berea College Commencement Address-Photographs (Box 85, Folder 10)
- Unfinished Business (1998)
  - Manuscript (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Drafts of Manuscript (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Planning and Outlines-Chapel Hill Conference, 10/27-28/97 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Planning and Outlines-Birmingham Conference, 11/14-16/98 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Planning and Outlines-Birmingham Conference, 11/14-16/98 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Chapel Hill Conference)-Outgoing (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (Chapel Hill Conference)-Incoming (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (Birmingham Conference)-Outgoing (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (Birmingham Conference)-Incoming (A-Mc) (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (Birmingham Conference-Incoming (Ma-Z) (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Publicity-Birmingham Conference (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Unfinished Business (1998)-Post Conference Materials (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Unfinished Business-Post Conference Materials (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Unfinished Business-Birmingham Conference Retrospective Report (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Unfinished Business-Birmingham Conference Retrospective Report (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Unfinished Business-Videotape of the Birmingham Conference (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Beyond Racism (2000)-Manuscript (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Beyond Racism-John Egerton’s Profiles (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Beyond Racism-Planning and Outlines (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Beyond Racism-Research and Background Materials (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Beyond Racism-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Beyond Racism-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - The Ralph McGill Lecture (2000)-Manuscript (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - The Ralph McGill Lecture-Research and Background Materials-Handwritten Notes (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - The Ralph McGill Lecture-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - The Ralph McGill Lecture-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - The Ralph McGill Lecture-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - The Ralph McGill Lecture-Publicity (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Commemorative Videotape-Popham Seminar 2000 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Nashville: An American Self-Portrait (2001)-Manuscript-Prologue, Chapters 1 and 2 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Nashville: An American Self-Portrait-Manuscript-Chapters 3,4,5,6 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Nashville: An American Self-Portrait-Manuscript-Chapters 7,8,9,10,11,12 (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Nashville: An American Self-Portrait-Manuscript-Full Circle, Patrons List, Appreciation, Staff List, Photographic Credits, Index (Box 88, Folder 11)
    Note: All other materials pertaining to this work are in the Metro Nashville Archives
- Oversize Box (Oversize Proof Pages and Photographs)
  Proofs for Nashville: The Faces of Two Centuries (1979) Oversize Photos for Generations (1983)
  Proofs for Southern Food (1987)
  Proofs for Shades of Gray (1991)
- Paige Box-Subject Files
  Five scrapbooks, c. 1950-1951, pertaining to education, especially in Pasadena, CA
- Generations---Twentieth Anniversary Edition (2003)
  - Manuscript for Revisions and Afterword (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles and Notes (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Reviews (Box 91, Folder 5)